Guide to the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 46 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 46 records, 1902-2014; 5739-002; 20.65 cubic feet 20 boxes and 2 oversized folders
  - Series III: Contract Negotiations, 1934-1999 (Box-folder 7/1-9/24)
    - Subseries E: Negotiating Committee Member Notes, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 9/14-9/24)
      - Puget Sound Chapter of the National Electrical Contractors Association Contract Negotiations: Gene Nelson's Notes, 1961 (Box-folder 9/20)
      - Negotiating Committee: Gene Nelson, 1962 (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Negotiating Committee: Joseph J. Vizzare, 1962 (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Negotiating Committee: Leonard Thomas, 1962 (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Negotiating Committee: Pat Costello, 1963 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Series IV: Office Files, 1945-1998 (Box-folder 9/25-11/12)
    The series is subdivided by function: Subseries A: Pamphlets and Handbooks; Subseries B: Insurance and Pensions; Subseries C: Legal Documents and Policies; Subseries D: Research; Subseries E: Correspondence; Subseries F: Constitutions and By-laws; Subseries G: Elections; Subseries H: Committee on Industrial Relations Petitions and Information; Subseries I: Overtime Pay Dispute: W.O. Gilliam. Subseries are further arranged chronologically.
    Series IV includes detailed records of the daily activities and research of the staff and officers of Local 46 from 1945-1998.
    - Subseries A: Pamphlets and Handbooks, 1968-1987 (Box-folder 9/25-9/27)
      - Coordinated Bargaining Pamphlet, circa 1968-1987 (Box-folder 9/25)
      - IBEW Pocket Handbooks, circa 1969-circa 1980 (Box-folder 9/26)
      - Todd Pacific Shipyards Employee Handbook, 1981 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Subseries B: Insurance and Pensions, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 9/28-9/30)
      - IBEW Local Union No. 46 Group Insurance Plan, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 9/28)
      - IBEW Pacific Coast Pension Fund, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 9/29)
      - Washington Metal Trades Health and Welfare Plan, 1968 (Box-folder 9/30)
    - Subseries C: Legal Documents and Policies, 1960-1976 (Box-folder 9/31-10/10)
      - Seattle Area Building Permits Analysis, June 1960 (Box-folder 9/31)
      - Seattle Area Building Permits Analysis, July 1960 (Box-folder 9/32)
      - Seattle Area Building Permits Analysis, August 1960 (Box-folder 9/33)
      - Seattle Area Building Permits Analysis, September 1960 (Box-folder 9/34)
      - Seattle Area Building Permits Analysis, December 1960 (Box-folder 9/35)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 9/36)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 9/37)
      - Brief in Behalf of Puget Sound Chapter, National Electrical Contractors Association for Local Union No. 46 IBEW, 1961 (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1962 (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1962 (Box-folder 10/3)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1962 (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Brief in Behalf of Puget Sound (Seattle) Chapter, National Electrical Contractors Association, 1962 (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Brief to the Council of Industrial Relations, 1962 (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Legislation: Electrical, 1962 (Box-folder 10/7)
      - State of Washington Rules and Regulations for Installing Electrical Wires and Equipment, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 10/8)
      - U.S. Department of Labor Ship Repairing Safety and Health Regulations, 1970 (Box-folder 10/9)
      - U.S. and Washington State Safety Standards, 1976 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Subseries D: Research, 1949-1998 (Box-folder 10/11-10/13)
      - Electrical progress of the Pacific Northwest 1949 (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Electrical Progress of the Pacific Northwest, 1949 (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Seattle Times Company Research Report, 1998 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Subseries E: Correspondence, 1945-1995 (Box-folder 10/14-11/2)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Correspondence, 1973-1995 (Box-folder 10/14)
      - Tyree Scott Postcard, March 1987 (Box-folder 10/15)
      - 75th Anniversary Invitation, 1989 (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Puget Sound Metal Trades Council Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 10/18)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 10/20)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1980 (Box-folder 10/21)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 10/22)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 10/23)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1985 (Box-folder 10/24)
      - Sparks Newsletter Correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 10/25)
      - Contract Negotiations Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 10/26)
      - IBEW Local 46 Correspondence 1 of 3, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 10/27)
      - IBEW Local 46 Correspondence 2 of 3, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 10/28)
      - IBEW Local 46 Correspondence 3 of 3, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 10/29)
      - National Electrical Contractors Association Correspondence, 1960-1976 (Box-folder 10/30)
      - Copy of Contract with Merritt-Chapman & Scott and The Savin Construction Corporation; Correspondence Regarding Subsistence for Electrical Workers, 1945-1957 (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Neon Sign Manufacturers of Washington: Unit Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Subseries F: Constitutions and By-laws, 1963-1991 (Box-folder 11/3-11/8)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 46 Constitution and By-laws, 1963-1984 (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Metal Trades Department Constitution and By-Laws, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Constitution and By-Laws, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Seattle Building and Construction Trades Council Constitution and By-laws, 1984 (Box-folder 11/6)
      - AFL-CIO Constitutions, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - Rules Governing AFL-CIO Local Central Bodies, 1991 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Subseries G: Elections, 1945-1989 (Box-folder 11/9-11/10)
      - Ramstead Election File, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 11/9)
      - Local 46 Election Ballots, 1989 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Subseries H: Committee on Industrial Relations Petitions and Information, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Subseries I: Overtime Pay Dispute: W.O. Gilliam, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Series V: Financial Records, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 11/13; 18/1; 11/14)
    The series is arranged chronologically.
    Series V includes accounts books for the local from 1928-1942.
    - Accounts Book, 1928-1937 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Accounts Book, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Accounts Book, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Series VI: Conferences and Conventions, 1955-2014 (Box-folder 11/15-12/10)
    The series is subdivided by originating body: Subseries A: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Convention; Subseries B: Metal Trades Department Convention; Subseries C: Metal Trades Department National Shipbuilding Conferences; Subseries D: Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Conventions; Subseries E: Pacific Coast Shipbuilding Conference; Subseries F: Washington State Labor Council Convention Proceedings; Subseries G: Anniversary Celebrations. Subseries are further arranged chronologic
    Series VI includes planning documents, proceedings, and ephemera from conventions, celebrations, and conferences that Local 46 either participated in or put on from 1955-2014.
    - Subseries A: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Conventions, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 11/15-11/16)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Convention Materials, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 11/15)
      - IBEW 34th International Convention, 1991 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Subseries B: Metal Trades Department Conventions, 1957-1987 (Box-folder 11/17-11/21)
      - Metal Trades Department Convention Proceedings, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 11/17)
      - Metal Trades Department Convention Proceedings (1 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 11/18)
      - Metal Trades Department Convention Proceedings (2 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 11/19)
      - Metal Trades Department Convention Proceedings, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 11/20)
      - Metal Trades Department Convention Proceedings, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Subseries C: Metal Trades Department National Shipbuilding Conferences, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 11/22-11/24)
      - An Analysis of Shipbuilding and Maritime Industry Labor Agreements, Prepared for the National Shipbuilding Conference, Metal Trades Department AFL-CIO, 1980 (Box-folder 11/22)
      - Metal Trades Department National Shipbuilding Conference Proceedings, October 1980-November 1984 (Box-folder 11/23)
      - Metal Trades Department National Shipbuilding Conference Proceedings, December 1986-December 1988 (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Subseries D: Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Conventions, 1955-1973 (Box-folder 11/25-12/3)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Convention Proceedings, January 1955-January 1961 (Box-folder 11/25)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Convention Proceedings, January 1963-January 1967 (Box-folder 12/1)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Convention Proceedings, May 1967-May 1971 (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Pacific Coast Metal Trades District Council Convention Proceedings, January 1973 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Subseries E: Pacific Coast Shipbuilding Conference, 1974 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Subseries F: Washington State Labor Council Convention Proceedings, 1986 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Subseries G: Anniversary Celebrations, 1964-2014 (Box-folder 12/6-12/10)
      - 50th Anniversary Guest Book and Program, 1964 (Box-folder 12/6)
      - 75th Anniversary Materials, 1989 (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Centennial program materials, 2014 (Box-folder 12/8)
      - 100th Anniversary Minutes Notebook, 2014 (Box-folder 12/9)
      - 100th Anniversary Photographs, 2014 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Series VII: Publications and Reports, 1922-2012 (Box-folder 12/11-14/10)
    The series is subdivided by originating body: Subseries A: Safety Committee Report; Subseries B: IBEW Journal; Subseries C: IBEW Local 46 Newsletter; Subseries D: The Electrical Worker: Reprint; Subseries E: Reprints and Anniversary Publications; Subseries F: Sparks Newsletters. Subseries are further arranged chronologically.
    Series VII includes publications and reports by Local 46 and various units within it, created from 1922-2012.
    - Subseries A: Safety Committee Report, May 1960 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Subseries B: IBEW Journal, 1922-2012 (Box-folder 12/12-14/4)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal Articles: Thumb Drive, 1922-circa 2012 (Box-folder 12/12)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1949 (Box-folder 12/13)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1950 (Box-folder 12/14)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1951 (Box-folder 12/15)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1952 (Box-folder 12/16)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1953 (Box-folder 13/1)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1954 (Box-folder 13/2)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1955 (Box-folder 13/3)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1956 (Box-folder 13/4)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1957 (Box-folder 13/5)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1958 (Box-folder 13/6)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1959 (Box-folder 13/7)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1962 (Box-folder 13/8)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1963 (Box-folder 13/9)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1964 (Box-folder 14/1)
      - Electrical Workers' Journal, 1965 (Box-folder 14/2)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, 1985 (Box-folder 14/3)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Journal, May 1986-June 1987 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Subseries C: IBEW Local 46 Newsletter, 1945-1963 (Box-folder 14/5-14/6)
      - IBEW Local 46 Newsletter, 1945 (Box-folder 14/5)
      - Newsletter IBEW, 1963 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Subseries D: The Electrical Worker: Reprints, 1902-1914 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Subseries E: Reprints and Anniversary Publications, 1964-1989 (Box-folder 14/8-14/9)
      - Various Anniversary Publications, 1964-1989 (Box-folder 14/8)
      - Reprints: Local and International Journal Issues from 1902, 1914 and 1947, 1989 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Subseries F: Sparks Newsletters, 1984-2004 (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Series VIII: Photographs and Historical Materials, 1915-2014
    The series is subdivided by function: Subseries A: Press Releases; Subseries B: Photographs; Subseries C: Historical Materials. Subseries are further arranged chronologically.
    Series VIII includes photographs and historical materials documenting the activities of Local 46 from 1915-2014.
    - Subseries A: Press Releases, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19/1)
      - Local Union 46 IBEW Press Releases Scrapbook, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Subseries B: Photographs, 1915-1999 (Box-folder 14/11-14/14; 21; 20/1-20/2; 14/17-14/19; 22; 14/20)
      - Historical Photographs, 1915-1988 (Box-folder 14/11)
      - Photographs and 75th Anniversary Materials, 1989 (Box-folder 14/12)
      - Materials and Photographs: 50th Anniversary, 1964 (Box-folder 14/13)
      - Old Timers Apprentice Banquet Photographs, 1969 (Box-folder 14/14)
      - Large format photograph, undated (Mapcase-folder 21)
      - Large format photograph, undated (Box-folder 20/2)
      - Photograph: Leon H. Brigham Field, 1999 (Box-folder 14/15)
      - Photographs, circa 1964 (Box-folder 14/16)
      - Photograph of International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers 29th Convention, 1970 (Box-folder 20/1)
      - Meeting Photographs, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 14/17)
      - Convention Group Photograph, circa 1965-circa 1980 (Box-folder 14/18)
      - Photographs and News Clippings, 1937-1975 (Box-folder 14/19)
      - Photograph of Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO, National Jobs Conference, 1976 (Mapcase-folder 22)
      - Photographs, 1954-1985 (Box-folder 14/20)
    - Subseries C: Historical Materials, 1925-2014 (Box-folder 14/21-15/8)
      - History Committee Binder Contents, 1967-1989 (Box-folder 14/21)
      - Copies of Historical Materials; IBEW History & Structure Booklet, 1989 (Box-folder 14/22)
      - Photographs and photocopies of certificates, agreements, press, and constitutions: Labeled "Info. for public gallery", 1996 (Box-folder 14/23)
      - Bob Gorman's Historical Materials 1 of 4, 1925-2014 (Box-folder 14/24)
      - Bob Gorman's Historical Materials 2 of 4, 1925-2014 (Box-folder 14/25)
      - Bob Gorman's Historical Materials 3 of 4, 1925-2014 (Box-folder 14/26)
      - Bob Gorman's Historical Materials 4 of 4, 1925-2014 (Box-folder 15/1)
      - Videocassette "Setting the Standard", 2001 (Box-folder 15/2)
      - Videocassette "Union Proud", undated (Box-folder 15/3)
      - Union Shop Cards, undated (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Bob Gorman: Correspondence; Realia, circa 1970-1985 (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Coffee Mug: Donated by Bob Gorman, undated (Box-folder 15/6)
      - IBEW Conference bags, undated (Box-folder 15/7)
      - Apprenticeship Record Book for Frank Carlyle Forman, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 15/8)